Lou Brian Lafuente

Software Engineer
Atlanta, GA | (678) 779-1161
www.loubrianlafuente.com/ | github.com/blafuente | linkedin.com/in/blafuente11 |
blafuente11@gmail.com

Student undertaking immersive program in full-stack web development and programming. Prior to this, I worked as field-support engineer for a packaging company providing hardware support to customers and also as a lead-technician for ANC Sports which specialized in LED equipment within sporting arenas and stadiums.

Software Development Skills

 Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, MySQL, Bootstrap, Flexbox AWS. React Native. HTML. CSS

Education

Southern Polytechnic State University | B.S. in Electrical Engineering Technology | Marietta, GA 2009 – December 2014

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA November 2018 - March 2019

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript, Python, including an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and MySQL.

Software Development Portfolio

The Professional Hobo | https://www.loubrianlafuente.com/project_front-end/index.html | github.com/ blafuente/project_front-end December 2018

- Part of a 4-person development team building a travel agency website that allows user to look up flight and hotel prices depending on a range of dates.
- User experience allows for the ability to search flights from U.S. cities for departure and arrival locations as well as a range of dates.
- User could also look up hotels in any U.S. city with a range of dates as well.
- Return data came from APIs.

The Budget Hobo | http://thebudgethobo.loubrianlafuente.com/ | github.com/ blafuente/backendProject Feburary 2019

- Member of a 4-person development team building a budget app site that allows users to create a user-login and log in their budget and expenses
- Primary responsibility included creating user database. Creating first time user register feature and logging in within the app/webpage.

Professional Work Experience

Ronchi America, LLC | Field Service Engineer | Atlanta, GA, February 2018 – June 2018

- Provide excellent service support for high quality, high tech PLC/Servo based automated packaging machinery all over USA.
- Trained under senior engineers on the functions and operations of packaging machinery while also traveling to customer sites to troubleshoot and inspect the machines.

ANC Sports | Game Day Operator, Lead Technician | Atlanta, GA June 2016 – February 2018

- Operate and maintain ANC's signage systems for all sporting and non-sporting events (including LED Displays, Rotational Signage and LED Operating Software. ANC's Clients in the market include the Atlanta Braves at Turner Field, and the Atlanta Dream and Atlanta Hawks at Philips Arena.
- Performed proactive assessments of onsite products before every event to ensure all signage systems will meet ANC's obligations to teams and sponsors.
- Was made lead technician after a month, and added responsibility of semi-managing local team and acted as ANC's representative to the company's clients in the market, including acting in a professional manner and adhering to all company policies and procedures